Finding Aid for Paul Winston McCracken papers, 1940-2011
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Papers, 1945-1996
  The Papers series contains publications, notes, book reviews, and speeches spanning from 1952 until 1996. A large gap occurs between 1959 until 1968 and the bulk of the papers are from the 1970s and 1980s. The scope of the Papers series is quite broad and includes subjects of state, national, and international importance.
  - 1945-1964
    - Research and the Role of the Economist, 9th District Conference of Agricultural Economists (Federal Reserve of Minneapolis), October 26, 1945 (Box 42)
    - The Future of Northwest Bank Deposits (Federal Reserve Bank -- Minneapolis, Minnesota) March 1946 (Box 42)
    - The Rising Tide of Bank Lending (Federal Reserve Bank -- Minneapolis, Minnesota), May 1947 (Box 42)
    - Forecasts of Postwar Business Activity, December 27, 1952 (Box 42)
    - Are Variable Annuities the Answer to Inflation? Journal of Finance, May 1956 (Box 42)
    - The Debt Problem and Economic Growth, Michigan Business Review, November 1956 (Box 42)
    - Practicing Political Economy, Economic Club, May 6, 1959 (Box 42)
    - Price Level Stability for or vs. Growth? Michigan Business Review, May 1961 (Box 42)
    - Unemployment in an Expanding Economy the Long View, Michigan Business Review, July 1964 (Box 42)
  - 1968
    - Economic Policy on the Spot. Michigan Banker's Association, Mackinac Island, Michigan, June 29, 1968 (Box 42)
  - 1969
    - Beyond 1969 Michigan Business Review, January 1969 (Box 42)
    - Beyond 1969 Economic Club of Detroit, September 22, 1969 (Box 42)
  - 1970
    - Unity in Diversity, Commencement Address (Huron College, Huron South Dakota) May 24, 1970 (Box 42)
    - Economic Priorities in the 1970s William K. McInally Memorial Lecture, University of Michigan, September 18, 1970 (Box 42)
  - 1972
    - Moving Toward External and Internal Economic Balance (Southwestern Economic Association Convention, San Antonio, Texas) March 31, 1972 (Box 42)
    - The Trouble with Phase II is..., Fortune, April, 1972 (Box 42)
    - From Ideas to Public Policy, Business Government Relations Council, West Virginia, June 23, 1972 (Box 42)
    - Economic Priorities in the 1970s and Moving Toward External and Internal Economic Balance, AEI, Reprint No. 2, August 1972 (Box 42)
    - Reconciling Domestic Requirements with a Liberal World Economy, El Mundo III Semana Economica Internacional, Barcelona, Spain, September 12, 1972 (Box 42)
    - An Economic Policy for the 1970s Western Michigan University, October 4, 1972 (Box 42)
    - Congress Can Regain Fiscal Control, Wall Street Journal, October 20, 1972 (Box 42)
    - The Changing Character of Japan-US Economic Relationships, Paper presented at a seminar on Japan at the University of Michigan, October 30, 1972 (Box 42)
    - Digest of Remarks, To the Third Annual Meeting of the American Supply Association, New York, November 11, 1972 (Box 42)
    - Will the New Economic Expansion Endure? Business Outlook Forum, Honolulu, Hawaii, November 13, 1972 (Box 42)
    - Comments on Monetary Policy in 1973 FRS, Washington, December 8, 1972 (Box 42)
    - The Practice of Political Economy, American Economic Association, Toronto, Canada, December 28, 1972 (Box 42)
  - 1973
    - Another New Economic Policy? Economic Club of Detroit, February 20, 1973 (Box 42)
    - Federal Budget Discipline and National Priorities of the '70s, Eighth Annual Financial Conference of the Conference Board, New York, NY, February 22, 1973 (Box 42)
    - The Changing Character of Japan-U.S. Economic Relationships, Michigan Business Review, March 1973 (Box 42)
    - Foundations for Economic Policy in the 1970s Moskowitz Lecture Series, College of Business and Public Administration, New York University, March 21, 1973 (Box 42)
    - Testimony to Subcommittee on Antitrust and Monopoly of the Committee on the Judiciary, United States Senate, New York, March 21, 1973 (Box 42)
    - Digest of Remarks to South Dakota State Univeristy (Economic Club Banquet), April 3, 1973 (Box 42)
    - Are we on a Boom-Bust Path? Economics Society of Michigan and Economics Section of the Michigan Academy of Science, Arts and Letters, Ann Arbor, April 6, 1973 (Box 42)
    - Sustainable Expansion: Have We Blown it Again? Mid-Year Economic Outlook Conference, Chicago Chapter of the American Statistical Association, June 7, 1973 (Box 42)
    - Overview of the Role of Energy in the Nation's Economy, National Financial and Business Writers Conference, Ann Arbor, June 12, 1973 (Box 42)
    - Digest of Remarks at the Management Briefing Seminars Sponsored by the University of Michigan Industrial Development Division and Michigan State Chamber of Commerce, July 30, 1973 (Box 42)
    - Economic Policy and the New Equality, Paper Delivered at the San Francisco Bay Area Council Outlook Conference, November 20, 1974 (Box 42)
    - Testimony before the Joint Economic Committee of the Congress, October 17, 1973 (Box 42)
    - Tax Changes for a Healthy Economy, 25th National Conference, Tax Foundation, Inc., New York, December 5, 1973 (Box 42)
  - 1974
    - The Changing Character of Japan-U.S. Economic Relationships, American Enterprise Institute Reprint, No. 20, December 1973 (Box 42)
    - Tax Changes for a Healthy Economy, Tax Review, January 1974 (Box 42)
    - Is There an Economic Outlook? Economic Club of Detroit, February 19, 1974 (Box 42)
    - Japan and the United States: Trade Issues and Monetary Alignment, Chicago Council on Foreign Relations and Japan Trade Center, February 19, 1974 (Box 42)
    - The New Equality, Michigan Business Review, March 1974 (Box 42)
    - Paper presented to the Business Council, Hot Springs, Virginia, October 12, 1973 (Box 42)
    - Testimony Before the Senate Committee on Appropriation, March 20, 1974 (Box 42)
    - Are the Grey Clouds Clearing? (Dr. Juster at ISR) April 8, 1974 (Box 42)
    - The Current Economic Outlook, Sixteenth Annual Forecasting Conference, New York Chapter, American Statistical Association, April 18, 1974 (Box 42)
    - A Strategy for Assuring the Future, Commencement Exercises, Saginaw Valley College, April 20, 1974 (Box 42)
    - The Problems of Adjustment in the U.S. Economy, The George S. Eccles Distinguished Lecture Series, Utah State University, May 2, 1974 (Box 42)
    - Competition and Market Concentration in the American Economy, with Thomas G. Moore, American Enterprise Institute (Box 42)
    - Inflation: The Program, American Banker's Assocation-National Governmental Affairs Conference/Symposium on Inflation, Washington, D.C., July 18, 1974 (Box 42)
    - Meet the Press Interview Transcript, July 21, 1974 (Box 42)
    - Will there be Econoimcs in 2024 ? Univeristy of Michigan Business Review (Vol. XXVI, No. 5), October 31, 1974 (Box 42)
    - The U.S. Economy Discovers the World, The University of Alabama Distinguished Lecture Series, September, 1974 (Box 42)
    - The World Economy Now Matters to the U.S., World Affairs Council, Wilmington, Delaware, December 9, 1974 (Box 42)
  - 1975
    - Scene Revisits: Dr. Paul McCracken, Ann Arbor Scene Magazine, Winter 1975 (Box 42)
    - New Perspectives for Retail Marketing: The Economy in 1975 National Merchants Association, January 7, 1975 (Box 42)
    - Statement before the Joint Economic Committee, January 23, 1975 (Box 42)
    - Statement before the Ways and Means Committee, January 29, 1975 (Box 42)
    - A Strategy for Michigan's Economic Future, Detroit Economic Club, February 10, 1975 (Box 42)
    - Can the Expansion of World Markets be Resumed? Federation of Korean Industries, Seoul, Korea, March, 1975 and Instituto de Estudios Superiores de la Empress, Universidad de Navarra, Madrid and Barcelona, Spain, April 29, 1975 (Box 42)
    - Our Underpinnings: A Bicentennial View (Cushing Oration, Annual Meeting of the American Association of Neurological Surgeons), April 8, 1975 (Box 42)
    - Is there a Strategy for the Future? (Albion College Commencement), May 10, 1975 (Box 42)
    - Steel and the Internationalization of Economic Life (International Iron and Steel Institute Ninth Annual Meeting and Conference, Mexico City, October 14, 1975 (Box 42)
    - Reflections on Economic Advising (Princeton University Conference on Advising the President, October 31, 1975 (Box 42)
    - Economic Shadows and Substance for 1976 (First Hawaiian Bank Business Outlook Forum) November 3, 1975 (Box 42)
    - Is Economic Progress Obsolete? (Clark University David J. Ott Memorial Lecture) November 14, 1975 (Box 42)
  - 1976
    - Statement to Committee on the Budget. US House of Representative, January 27, 1976 (Box 42)
    - Doing Business in the Emerging Economy, Economic Club of Detroit, February 9, 1976 (Box 42)
    - Reflections on Economic Advising, March 1976 (Box 42)
    - Statement Before the Senate Budget Committee, March 10, 1976 (Box 42)
    - Government Spending: The Renaissance of Fiscal Discipline? Paper presented to the Conference of the Ontario Economic Council, Toronto, March 15, 1976 (Box 42)
    - Statement to the Joint Economic Committee, March 10, 1976 (Box 42)
    - The Economy Today as it Relates to Consumer Credit. Paper delivered at the National Installment Credit Conference, American Banker's Association, Miami Beach, April 5, 1976 (Box 42)
    - The Car is Freedom, Total Magazine, Summer 1976 (Box 42)
    - Statement Before the Committee to Investigate a Balanced Federal Budget, Washington, D.C., May 7, 1976 (Box 42)
    - Structural Changes in the World-Their Impact on Monetary and Economic Policy, General Assembly of the International Savings Bank Institute, Geneva, Switzerland, June 2, 1976 (Box 42)
    - Is Sustainable Economic Growth Still Possible? Assembly on US-Japan Economic Policy, Tokyo, Japan, June 11, 1976 (Box 42)
    - An Elder Statesman's Advice to a CEA Chairman, Western Michigan University, September 22, 1976 (Box 42)
    - From Economic Analysis to Policy, paper delivered at the Sixth Annual Meeting of the Illinois Economic Association, St. Louis, Missouri, October 22, 1976 (Box 42)
    - The Election, the Economy and the Prospects for Prosperity, Twenty-Ninth Annual Manufacturer/Distributor Conference of the Automotive Warehouse Distributors Association, Las Vegas, Nevada, October 26, 1976 (Box 42)
    - Our National Economic Plan, University of Arkansas, Little Rock, Arkansas, October 28, 1976 (Box 42)
    - The Hazards of 76, Economic Outlook USA, Winter 1976 (Box 42)
  - 1977
    - 1977 A Year of Resumed Expansion? G. Tsai & Co. Inc., January 5, 1977 (Box 42)
    - Testimony of Paul W. McCracken Before the Senate Budget Committee, Washington, D.C. January 11, 1977 (Box 42)
    - On a strategy for the Future (Commencement Exercises, University of Michigan, Flint), January 13, 1977 (Box 42)
    - What Makes America? Economic Club of Detroit, February 7, 1977 (Box 42)
    - Fiscal Policy for Growth with Price Stability, 1977 Financial Conference, The Conference Board, New York, February 24, 1977 (Box 42)
    - Our National Economic Plan, (AEI Reprint No. 63), February 1977 (Box 42)
    - The U.S. Economic Outlook, Fourth Canadian Financial Conference, The Conference Board in Canada, Montreal, June 28, 1977 (Box 42)
    - Testimony before the Senate Banking Committee, Washington, D.C., July 20, 1977 (Box 42)
    - What Our Society Should Be all About, The Conference Board Magazine, July 1977 (Box 42)
    - Is Sustained Economic Expansion an Obsolete Idea? Roosovelt University's Education for Freedom Award Dinner, Chicago, October 4, 1977 (Box 42)
    - Towards Full Employment and Price Stability, Conference Board International Financial Conference, Brussels, Belgium, October 25, 1977 (Box 42)
    - The Nature of the Capital Problem in the Coming Decade, Capital Formation Conference, Continental Illinois National Bank and Trust Company, Chicago, November 29, 1977 (Box 42)
  - 1978
    - Observations on the Outlook.Economic Outlook USA, Winter 1978 (Box 43)
    - This Crucial Economic Year, Economic Club of Detroit, February 6, 1978 (Box 43)
    - Can the Industrial Economies Regain Their Stability? International Debate on the Response of the Principal Occidental Power to the Economic Challenges of Our Times, Federation Nationale des Clubs Perspectives et Realites, Paris, February 11, 1978 (Box 43)
    - Towards Full Employment and Price Stability, The C. Woody Thompson Lecture, Midwest Economics Association, Chicago, April 6, 1978 (Box 43)
    - Can A Stable Economy Be Regained? The Second W. Frank Hipp Lecture, University of South Carolina, April 27, 1978 (Box 43)
    - Reducing the Unemployment-Inflation Rates, 1978 (Box 43)
    - The Inflation-Unemployment Dilemma: Can Keynesian Economics Cope? Fifth Canadian Financial Conference, The Conference Board in Canada, Toronto, June 27, 1978 (Box 43)
    - Testimony before the House Committee on Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs, August 11, 1978 (Box 43)
    - Beyond Intellectual Mechanics (first delivered at the William F. Butler Award Luncheon, New York Association of Business Economists), September 26, 1978 (Box 43)
    - Toward a New Balance in the World Economy, XVIII Alumni Assembly, Instituto de Estudios Superiores de la Empresa, University of Navarre, Barcelona, Spain, October 13, 1978 (Box 43)
    - Economic Developments and the Structure of the World Economy, Nordic Labor Market Conference, Denmark, October 25, 1978 (Box 43)
    - Review of Reflections of an Economic Policy Maker by Arthur F. Burns (American Enterprise Institute), 1978 (Box 43)
    - The Management of Economic Policy in a Political Democracy. The Burkett Miller Memorial Lecture University of Tennessee, November 15, 1978 (Box 43)
    - Toward a More Enduring Expansion?, Economic Outlook U.S.A., December 1978 (Box 43)
    - Can Capitalism Survive? Prochnow book chapter, February 1979 (Box 43)
    - We Can Have Low Rates of Inflation and Unemployment Detroit News Magazine, February 4, 1979 (Box 43)
    - 1979 A Prologue to What? Economic Club of Detroit, February 7, 1979 (Box 43)
    - Digest of Remarks to the Subcommittee on Economic Stabilization of the Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs, Washington, D.C., February 7, 1979 (Box 43)
    - Inflation, Profits, and the American Economy. Paper presented to the Conference on Financial Reporting and Changing Prices, Financial Accounting Standards Board, New York, May 31, 1979 (Box 43)
    - A Strategy for Assuring the Future: Remarks at the Commencement Exercises, Northwestern Michigan College, June 3, 1979 (Box 43)
    - Conjuctural Problems in the U.S. Economy, Chicago Chapter of the American Statistical Association, June 6, 1979 (Box 43)
    - Preface to Jones Book, June 3, 1979
    - The Economic Situation Life Officers Investment Seminar. June 18, 1979 (Box 43)
    - Thoughts on 1979-and Beyond MGIC Monthly Newsletter, 1979 (Box 43)
    - Statement to the Joint Economic Committee of the Congress, July 13, 1979 (Box 43)
    - The U.S. in the World Economy, 1980 Business Outlook Conference, New York, September 20, 1979 (Box 43)
    - The Outlook for 1980 First Hawaiian Bank Conference in Honolulu, October 16, 1979 (Box 43)
    - An Effective Economic Plan Paper Moorman Lecture Series Culver-Stockton College, Canton, Missouri, October 30, 1979 (Box 43)
    - Can a Stable Dollar be Re-Established? Summary of address delivered to the National Committee for Monetary Reform Sixth Annual Conference, New Orleans, November 2, 1979 (Box 43)
    - Inflation Policy Task Force Report, 1979 (Box 43)
    - Can the United States Regain Its Capability for Orderly Economic Expansion? College of Business Administration, University of Minnesota, November 7, 1979 (Box 43)
  - 1980
    - The Uncertain 1980s Economic Outlook USA, Winter 1980 (Box 43)
    - Digest of Remarks at National Retail Merchants Association, New York, January 14, 1980 (Box 43)
    - The Economic Outlook for the 1980s University of Santa Clara, California, Fifth Economic Symposium, Center for Leadership Development, January 21, 1980 (Box 43)
    - Can Capitalism Survive? (AEI, Reprint No. 104), February 1980 (Box 43)
    - Is There Hope for the 1980s? Economic Club of Detroit, February 11, 1980 (Box 43)
    - Economic Policy at a Decision Point, Banking Institute Washington University Business School, St. Louis, February 26, 1980 (Box 43)
    - Some Ethical Questions in Our Economic Problems Comments at the Chamber of Commerce Symposium, Los Angeles, February 29, 1980 (Box 43)
    - Statement Presented to the Senate Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, March 10, 1980 (Box 43)
    - The U.S. and the World Economy, Seventh Annual Dinner Meeting, Virginia Association of Economists, "William A. Sandridge Lecture", George Mason University, March 20, 1980 (Box 43)
    - U.S. Leadership in the World Economy, Mitsubishi Research Institute, Tokyo, Japan, April 7, 1980 (Box 43)
    - Can the American Economy Regain its Vitality? 1980 Briscoe Lecture in Banking, College of Business Administration, Texas Tech University, April 19, 1980 (Box 43)
    - A Strategy for Reaching Century 21 Commencement Address, Graduate School of Business Administration, University of Michigan, May 2, 1980 (Box 43)
    - A Strategy for Reaching Century 21 Commencement Address St. Anselm's College, May 18, 1980 (Box 43)
    - Statement to Joint Economic Committee, Washington D.C., May 29, 1980 (Box 43)
    - A Strategy for Reaching Century 21 Commencement Address, Graduate School of Business Administration, University of Michigan, May 2, 1980 (Box 43)
    - A Strategy for Reaching Century 21 Commencement Address St. Anselm's College, May 18, 1980 (Box 43)
    - Statement to Joint Economic Committee, Washington D.C., May 29, 1980 (Box 43)
    - The Strategy of Economic Policy in the 1980s Ministry of Economic Affairs of France ("How Can Developed Countries Adapt to the New Context of the 80s") Paris, June 4, 1980 (Box 43)
    - Economic Developments and Energy, Abstract of comments of "Economic Developments and Energy" 48th Annual Edison Electric Institute Convention, June 11, 1980 (Box 43)
    - Reflections of an Economic Policy Maker: review article of Arthur F. Burns, Reflections of An Economic Policy Maker (American Enterprise Institute Journal of Economic Literature), June 1980 (Box 43)
    - The Corporation and the Liberal Order, Paper presented to the Summer Seminar 1980 "The Corporation: A Theological Inquiry?" sponsored by the American Enterprise Institute and Department of Religion of Syracuse University, July 8, 1980 (Box 43)
    - A Policy for Economic Progress, Borg-Warner Lecture at Cornell University, October 27, 1980 (Box 43)
    - Revitalizing the American Economy: A Strategy for the 1980s. American Enterprise Institute for Public Policy Research, Fourth Annual Public Policy Week, December 9, 1980 (Box 43)
    - Remarks to the Fourth Annual Francis Boyer Dinner, Washington, D.C., December 11, 1980 (Box 43)
  - 1981
    - Reindustrialization of America (Tax Foundation), 1981 (Box 43)
    - Legislative Conference on the Economy, Willamette University, January 7, 1981 (Box 43)
    - The Government, Business and Labor Perspective, Remarks at "The Japanese Automotive Industry: Model and Challenge for the Future" The University of Michigan, January 14, 1981 (Box 43)
    - Is There Still Hope for the 1980s ? Economic Club of Detroit, February 2, 1981 (Box 43)
    - A New Age Begins: America's Diminished Role in the World Economy, Michigan Quarterly Review, Spring 1981 (Box 43)
    - Economic Expectations The New U.S. Automotive Industry, University of Michigan Management Briefing Seminar, Traverse City, July 27-29, 1981 (Box 43)
    - Reagan Economic Policy and Its Implications for U.S.-Japan Relations, Fifth Shimoda Conference, Japan, September 2, 1981 (Box 43)
    - U.S. Fiscal and Monetary Policies, Paper delivered at the "Conference on Economic Policies in the U.S.," Paris, September 10, 1981 (Box 43)
    - Where Do Fiscal and Monetary Policies Go From Here? Tulane University, Murphy Distinguished Lecturer Series, September 22, 1981 (Box 43)
    - 1981 Still Has a Chance, Economic Outlook USA, Winter 1981 (Box 43)
    - Where Do Fiscal and Monetary Policies Go From Here? Tulane University, Murphy Distinguished Lecturer Series, September 22, 1981 (Box 43)
    - Prospects for Economic Revitalization, George Mason University, September 14, 1981 (Box 43)
    - New Directions for Economic Policy: An American Perspective. Presentation at the Business Outlook 1982 Conference Board of Canada, October 1, 1981 (Box 43)
    - Is There Hope for the Economy? The Second Armand G. Erpf Invitational Symposium on American Private Enterprise. Berry College, Mount Berry, Georgia, October 26, 1981 (Box 43)
    - Digest of Remarks "Can This Tangled Economy Be Straightened Out" Bryant Lecture Series, The University of North Carolina at Greensboro, N.C., November 6, 1981 (Box 43)
    - The U.S. Economy in 1981 Dow Banking Corp., Zurich, Switzerland, December 7, 1981 (Box 43)
    - Review of Roger A. Freeman, "The Wayward Welfare State" (Hoover Institute, 1981)Detroit News, December 23, 1981 (Box 43)
  - 1982
    - Prospects for Economic Revitalization Economic Impact No. 37, 1982 (Box 43)
    - The Average Cycle and 1982 Economic Outlook USA, Winter 1982 (Box 43)
    - Summary of Remarks at NRMA Meeting on January 11, 1982 (Box 43)
    - Can Washington's Economic Program Work? Economic Club of Detroit, February 8, 1982 (Box 43)
    - Testimony to the Committee on the Budget, U.S. House of Representatives, March 9, 1982 (Box 43)
    - "Industry at the Crossroads." Opening Statement at the Second U.S.-Japan Automotive Industry Conference, Ann Arbor, March 16, 1982 (Box 43)
    - Restoring Our Prosperity, April 26, 1982 (Box 43)
    - Is There a Future for the Class of 1982? Commencement Address, Northern Michigan University, May 1, 1982 (Box 43)
    - Outlook for the Economy in 1982 William R. Biggs/Gilmore Association Luncheon, Kalamazoo, MI., May 4, 1982 (Box 43)
    - Is Economic Progress Obsolete? International Monetary Conference, Session 1, Vancouver, Canada, May 25, 1982 (Box 43)
    - Review of Kenneth W. Dam, "The Rules of the Game: Reform and Evolution in the International Monetary System," August 1982 (Box 43)
    - The Economic Outlook, If Any, Paper delivered at First Hawaiian Bank Conference, Honolulu, Hawaii, November 9, 1982 (Box 43)
    - Reagonomics: A Mid-Term Examination. Paper delivered at New York University Annual Homecoming Day for the Charles C. Moskowitz Memorial Lecture Series, December 4, 1982 (Box 44)
  - 1983
    - Notes on Budget and Monetary Policy, Digest of Remarks to the House Budget Committee, February 1983 (Box 44)
    - Review of Richard H. Fink, "Supply Side Economics: A Critical View" (Altheia Books, University Publications), 1983 (Box 44)
    - The Swallows of Spring, Economic Outlook USA article, January 10, 1983 (Box 44)
    - "... and a Time to Expand. Paper delivered to the Economic Club of Detroit, February 14, 1983 (Box 44)
    - The Knife-Edge Balance of the World Economy, 46th Annual Chicago World Trade Conference for presentation of the Fowler-McCracken Report, April 18, 1983 (Box 44)
    - The U.S. Economy in the World Context, Paper delivered at the Conference Panel program at the tenth Anniversary of the Geneva Association, Venice, Italy, 1983 (Box 44)
    - Forces Shaping the World Economic Outlook, May 2, 1983 (Box 44)
    - McCracken on Michigan's Economy, Detroit Engineer, April / May 1983 (Box 44)
    - The Economy's Fundamental Problem. Written for publication in Enterprise, August 12, 1983 (Box 44)
    - Is Industrial Policy for the U.S.? National Association of Business Economists' 25th Annual Luncheon, September 30, 1983 (Box 44)
    - Remarks at the World Forum, August 28, 1983 (Box 44)